RG 034, State Salvage Committee
Connecticut State Library
State Salvage Committee records
1941-1945
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Sate Salvage Committee
17.5 cubic feet
The State Salvage Committee informed the public of the need for conserving scarce materials and assisted in collecting and utilizing salvage during World War II.
RG034
T002688
Historical Note
The State Salvage Committee was organized in December 1941 as part of the State Defense Council (later known as the War Council). It also served as the Connecticut agent of the General Salvage Section of the Conservation Bureau of the U. S. Office of Production Management. The Committee informed the public of the need for conserving scarce materials and assisted in collecting and utilizing salvage. It worked with local town salvage committees and with scrap and waste dealers on an Advisory Salvage Board. The Committee appears to have functioned as an independent agency, despite its origin as a part of the Defense Council and its various connections with Federal Government agencies (O.P.M., W.P.B., etc.). It went out of business in early 1945.
Scope and Content
The record group contains minutes and agendas of meetings, drafts and copies of speeches and reports, lists of local and industry committee members, incoming and outgoing correspondence, town production cards, publicity materials such as newsletters and photographs, administrative subject files, and town correspondence and memoranda files.
Related Material
RG 005:029, Raymond E. Baldwin gubernatorial records, 1943-1946 (under "Salvage")
RG 050, War Council, 1940-1945
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. State Salvage Commission
Subjects:
Connecticut. State Salvage Commission -- Records and correspondence; Salvage (Waste, etc.)
Document Types:
Agendas (administrative records); Card files; Clippings; Correspondence; Membership lists; Memorandums; Minutes; Press releases; Prints; Radio scripts; Reports; Speeches
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1941-1945
  - 1. Executive and organizational papers, 1941-1945 (Box 1-3)
    Contains minutes and agenda of meetings, drafts and copies of speeches and reports, lists of local and industry committee members, correspondence with members of the salvage Committee and other materials.
    Grouped by subject or correspondent.
  - 2. Production record cards, 1942-1945 (Box 3)
    Cards showing, for each town, the quantity of metal, rags, paper, tin and grease salvage.
    Alphabetical by town.
  - 3. Publicity material, 1942-1945 (Box 4-6)
    Samples and files of publicity and public relations materials used to promote public interest and participation. Included are scripts of radio programs, glossy prints of pictures, press releases (with index),
    The Scrapper
    and
    Connecticut Salvage
    , clippings, a flag, etc.
  - 4. Subject file, 1941-1945
    Contains general program and administrative correspondence, reports, memoranda and related material.
    Alphabetical by subject.
    - A-Billboards (Box 7)
    - Bills of lading-Bureau of Mines (Box 8)
    - Buttons-Depot (Box 9)
    - E-Farm Press Scrap Drive (Box 10)
    - Fats-Governor (Box 11)
    - Grease-Industrial (Box 12)
    - Industry-Institute of Scrap Iron and Steel (Box 13)
    - Institute of Scrap Iron and Steel-Maps (Box 14)
    - Milk Dealers Association-P (Box 15)
    - Paper (Box 16)
    - Paper-Pictures (Box 17)
    - Phonograph records-Regional Bulletins (Box 18)
    - Rejects-School plan (Box 19)
    - Schools-Spinning (Box 20)
    - Sponge iron-Steel (Box 21)
    - T-Weekly Progress Report (Box 22)
  - 5. Town file, 1941-1945
    Contains correspondence, reports and memoranda concerning local salvage programs.
    - Andover-Bridgeport (Box 23)
    - Bridgewater-Danbury (Box 24)
    - Darien-Essex (Box 25)
    - Fairfield-Hampton (Box 26)
    - Hartford-Lyme (Box 27)
    - Madison-Monroe (Box 28)
    - Montville-New Haven (Box 29)
    - New London-Norwich (Box 30)
    - Old Lyme-Roxbury (Box 31)
    - Salem-Stamford (Box 32)
    - Sterling-Warren (Box 33)
    - Washington-West Hartford (Box 34)
    - Weston-Woodstock (Box 35)